ALOIS M. RENGGLI

377 Harbour Way Lakehills, TX 78063 Tel: (315) 679-8929 alois.renggli@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE: Position as a Project Engineer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Army Aviation Officer with over 13 years of military service. Creative, versatile, and motivated professional with management experience ranging from small groups to organizations with over 100 employees. Technically-fluent problem-solver that is innovative and adaptable. Experience includes managing sensitive materials, administrative support, recruiting, helicopter maintenance operations, and mentoring employees.

- Secret Security Clearance
- Independent
- Disciplined

- Self-controlled
- Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint
- HTML, CSS, Git, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, MySQL, Spring

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Electrical Engineering with Honors, United States Military Academy, West Point, NY

GPA 3.64 / Eta Kappa Nu (Tota Phi Chapter) / Phi Kappa Phi

Full Stack Developer, CodeUp, San Antonio, TX (Graduating in November 2018)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Program Administrator - Special Operations Aviation Planner

U.S. Army, Fort Polk, LA

September 2017 – Present

June 2016 - August 2017

- Expanded training area for Special Operations aviation by over 50% though coordination with the Federal Aviation
 Administration, Department of the Army Representative, Air Force Special Operations Command, Air Traffic Control
 representatives, and other government organizations.
- Planned and coordinated aviation support (Unmanned Aircraft Systems, fixed wing, and rotary wing) for Special Operations
 Forces for 10 simulated combat rotations at the Joint Readiness Training Center.
- Established and enforced standardized policies for Special Operations aviation requests and data collection in authorized operational areas.

Operations Officer - Aviation Maintenance

U.S. Army, Fort Hood, TX

- Successfully planned and executed a simulated combat rotation for my maintenance troop at the National Training Center in 2017. My troop was assessed as one of the best aviation maintenance troops to complete a rotation in over 2 years (approximately 20 rotations).
- Directed daily maintenance operations of 24 AH-64E helicopters and 8 RQ-7B Shadow Unmanned Aerial Systems valued in excess of \$960 million. Exceeded the Army standard for operational readiness rate of aviation assets by over 10%.
- Supervised an organization of 115 employees with tools and equipment valued in excess of \$14 million.

Program Administrator – Helicopter Operations

May 2010 - June 2016

U.S. Army, Fort Drum, NY; Fort Rucker, AL; Fort Hood, TX; Afghanistan

- Prepared my assigned personnel for a combat rotation to Afghanistan in 2013 through rigorous training. Completed a 9 month operation in Afghanistan with no combat injuries to personnel or loss of equipment.
- Planned and managed daily operations for brigade and battalion sized organizations in excess of 4,000 Soldiers.
- Prepared operational records and reports for GS-15 rank equivalent personnel.
- Supervised and managed daily operations of 24 Soldiers in a platoon of 5 UH-60M helicopters and responsible for the accountability and maintenance of sensitive equipment valued in excess of \$30 million.

Infantryman April 2001 - June 2006

U.S. Army, Camp Smith, NY; Iraq

- Conducted daily personal interactions with culturally diverse personnel while deployed to Iraq in 2004.
- Responsible for over \$20,000 of professional equipment and sensitive items with no loss or damage over a 5 year period.